Well, it's 6:00, so we'll go ahead and
get started. Um
go ahead and
do roll call.
And Gary
Is he online?
I I did you hear anything from Gary as
far as him being absent?
>> I didn't hear anything.
>> He's on his vacation. I don't know if he
was how long that was going to be, but
>> Got you. Maybe it was over
a couple months.
Okay.
>> [clears throat]
>> David Bender
>> Here.
>> Josh Chrysler
>> Elizabeth Degringer
>> Here.
>> Patrick Bustos Oh, he
he actually did contact me and tell me
he was going to be absent. Uh Kelly
Severe
>> Here.
>> Patrick Bond
>> And Chuck Broderick
>> Here.
>> Okay. Well,
I think we have a quorum.
Uh
does anyone want to
make a motion to approve the minutes
from the last meeting?
>> I'll move.
>> I'll second.
>> Any discussion?
I do have one little
spelling correction. It's
Conwell, not Cromwell.
I know.
>> [laughter]
>> Any other comments on the
minutes?
Okay.
Uh all in favor
say aye.
>> Aye.
>> Any opposed?
>> Um does anyone need to make any
disclosures?
Conflicts of interest? Okay.
Um,
do we have any audience online?
see we've got
I guess just do you want to I I'm pretty
I'm sorry, I just forgot your name, so I
was like, uh
Um, do you do you want to address the
board for anything or you just
hanging out and listening? Okay.
Okay.
Okay, I guess city council.
>> Thank you, Madam Chair, members of the
board. Even though we had a long meeting
last night, it
>> [clears throat]
>> was mostly centered around a couple
things.
And really we
mostly had referrals, but we had a
public hearing last night on some
annexation of a
1,259.91
acres located in west of Round Top Road
and adjacent to Happy Jack Road.
And Charles [clears throat] might want
to touch on this a little bit later,
but there was some mix-up in some of the
families out there that have the
re-chants that thought that they were
part of the annexation.
Uh,
this is where our freshwater treatment
plant is.
So, uh
I think that's uh
related to the states. That that's most
of the people that came in
spoke against it or live in that area.
Uh, but most [clears throat] of this
area is actually city land,
which uh
I found ironic cuz a lot of these people
usually
believe in
their uh
property rights.
I guess when it comes to the city, we
don't have the same property rights.
Uh,
we'll see how this goes in the future.
Uh, but it but that was pretty
interesting. the other one that I think
you guys were really
uh, paying attention to was that the
finance committee
and some of my colleagues approved $5
million of reserves to go toward the
Reed Avenue corridor project. Uh,
and this is uh, only going to be
expended if we reach a final agreement
with the Burlington Northern Santa Fe
Railroad.
That passed
7 to 2, I believe.
And then, uh,
and the last one,
uh, the DDA district
uh, agreed to expand to include the
Snyder grocery store.
And after that, it was just mostly
referrals. We had about
20 referrals to both the public service
committee and the finance committee.
Uh,
and the other thing at the end of the
agenda was we
designated Dr. Mark Greenlee to be the
delegate to the LAMB conference and
Mayor Patrick Collins to be the
alternate.
Any questions?
>> [laughter]
>> Does anyone have any questions
for City Councilman Eskamoe?
Well, I know you have other
>> Yeah, I know.
>> things to get to, so
>> I'm good. I'm good.
>> Yeah.
>> If you have any more questions, I think
Charles can handle this.
>> Well, then thank you for coming in.
>> All right.
Thank you, Madam Chair, members.
>> Uh,
yeah.
Planning and development reports.
This got upgraded. I feel like it's a
lot louder for some reason. Or am I just
crazy? Okay.
>> I know, it's there's no possible way it
was upgraded.
>> [laughter]
>> Should have asked.
>> We just flipped over the cassette tape
to record on the other side.
>> Oh, okay.
>> And the gerbil's running a little
quicker to make the
audio system work better, so it's all
good. No, um next is uh planning
development department updates, correct?
Okay. All right. As Councilman Aschmann
mentioned, we did have that annexation
that was out there. And the uh the issue
that was out there was there
was a
incorrect name that was posted in the
staff report. It was a the William S.
Cox Revocable Trust was the annexation
applicant. Um they had acquired another
piece of land from the
uh Cox Ranch LLC. However, the county
assessor is
it's fair to say years behind on updates
to that GIS map they have online. So,
the property ownership was wrong. I
don't think it's the county assessor,
it's the county IT department's very far
behind on getting information to the GIS
folks. So, just word of caution, that
map is not accurate. So, it's it's
self-admitted that it should not be
relied on for accuracy. So, if you want
zoning, it's completely wrong. At least
for city zoning.
So, that's going on. But anyway, um
yeah, the residents out in the um
Rolling Hills neighborhood were very
concerned because they thought they were
being annexed. I mean, it's very clear
that this is about a half mile away from
them. So, there was just some concern
there. One thing that was noted is on
the property that's being annexed, which
is for a future business park
development, um there's an old mausoleum
that is out there on the southern side.
So, if you're ever driving out on
Highway 210 and you look to the north,
you'll see a mausoleum that looks out of
place. Sounds like some of you may have
not seen this before, but some are
familiar. So, I don't know what the
history is of it, um but it will be a
discussion point as we move through the
site plan uh to see what their
intentions are for it or there's a
reservation or an easement to let it
remain. So, it's on our horizon.
Um secondly, with
um our department, we are looking for
ways to be more efficient. Um one of the
ways we're going to be more efficient is
we're looking at changing the way that
we document our meetings. Um we're going
to be transitioning in the next few
months to um essentially action minutes
that will just identify who's here, what
the motion was, who made comments, and
what the the vote was. Um in response to
that, we will be uploading all of our
videos to our YouTube channel and we'll
have an actual link
to that on our agenda and minutes page.
And we'll probably go above and beyond
with our action minutes. We'll actually
put a time stamp on there as to where
the discussion starts. So, if people
want to hear exactly what happened, why
13 people commented, they can go
um take a look at it there.
Um it's really tough and challenging to
do the verbatim minutes um and it's a
lot of very time-consuming.
Um secondly, let's see.
What else do we have going on? Um we are
in the early stages of
uh bringing forward a certificate of
appropriateness to you all for
demolition and
rebuild of a garage on the rear portion
of a house in a historic district's
contributing structure. So, that will be
coming forward to you all at the next
meeting. Uh one thing that was
surprising with that when we reread the
code again is just the advanced
deadlines that we have for publishing
the report at least 15 days prior to the
meeting and also delivering it
physically
by hand or via mail. So, we might be
looking at um doing some updates to our
city municipal code to bring that into
the 21st century.
>> I did receive that letter by the way,
so.
>> That was one of the archaic things.
That's step one. That's first piece of
physical mail that you all get. You'll
get a physical staff report as well. So,
beware, paper cuts happen.
So, we have that.
Um
There was an announcement that was made
today. I don't know if you saw the
announcement by Microsoft um that they
are developing a an apartment 3000 acre
addition to our business park on the
south east portion of the community. So,
that's moving forward as well as a bunch
of other um industrial park projects.
So, we have no shortage of work coming
our direction.
Um and I believe our council or
governing body meetings will be long
as we move forward.
Um other than that, I don't have any
Oh,
uh Councilman Scoville did mention that
the DDA district uh did vote to or they
had recommended that their boundaries be
increased to include the Snyder Street
grocery store over on Snyder just on the
west side there at about 21st, 22nd
Street right over there. Um that did
pass uh second reading last night by the
governing body, so that's moving forward
and that will make it a
uh contributor to the It'll be part of
the DDA district um effective January
1st when the tax rolls are updated.
One other final piece that I will touch
on is we have our
County Pocket annexation is still
pending.
Um at the last
one of the more recent meetings of the
governing body, they postponed action on
that until their first meeting in
November. Um so, it's just hanging out
there in in limbo right now. Our goal is
to move forward with uh
ordinances that
um address some of the right to farm um
and the food freedom act
and uh electric fences and anything else
that could be agriculture and livestock
related. So, we're moving forward with
that.
One of the unintended consequences of
that was it did
uh delay a city-wide blight study, which
was under
was waiting for that to be complete to
essentially do blanket designation as
blight for the city to allow for the URA
urban renewal toolbox essentially be
used by any property owners. That's had
a trickle-down effect and has delayed
probably about four or five housing um
developments that were seeking to use
urban renewal um
tax incentive dollars. So, um
I'm working with those folks to see if
there's an alternative path forward on a
couple of different um developments.
So, with that, that's those are the
updates I have. Aaron, do you have any
additional items?
All right.
>> So, you want to have any questions?
Rush?
>> I Yeah, um
well, I've always noticed that mausoleum
and been curious about it. So, I'll be
interested to hear what you sort of
uncover about the history of it. Um
but my question is and I I see we have a
line item for it later on, but just
about that 418 West 1st Avenue. Um I'm
curious if you could
um sort of walk us through
how it's coming to us as a board because
does it have like a covenant just on
that specific address or something
because it's not in one of the
protective I mean, it's you right,
there's no like protective overlay or
anything in that neighborhood.
>> Yes, I can walk it walk you all through
that real quick. However, I I'm not
going to do specific code citations. I'm
not sure which ones they are off the top
of my head. Um the there's two
provisions that we have in our municipal
code regarding a review of historic
structures. One of them is the
Governor's Mansion Historic Overlay
District, which that's right there. It's
about uh you know, a couple square
blocks. Any changes, regardless of if
it's contributing or not, they get
reviewed. And you grant a COA.
The other piece is if it is a building
that is identified as a contributing
structure in a historic district, and
they're proposing demolition or
relocation of it,
then it's triggered to have to have
permission by this board. Um
We did look at this. This is an actual
demolition of a piece of the structure,
an attached garage.
Um and then it will have a rebuild. So,
what we're looking [clears throat] at
and reviewing is number one, the
demolition, is it going to detract from
the historic fabric of that district?
And number two, is the um addition that
is replacing it essentially in harmony
with the uh preservation standards of I
think it's preservation brief uh 14
is the one that talks about appropriate
additions. So, that's what you're
looking at in this specific case.
>> And so then, you'll be sending us
physical mail in
to basically 2 weeks from now that sort
of outlines everything that we need to
look at with the building before
the May board meeting.
>> Chair, three, that's correct.
>> Thanks.
>> Any other questions for planning and
development?
Okay, we'll move on to strategic uh
goals report, uh National Register of
Historic Places.
Elizabeth, do you want to
>> Yeah, um I can give quick update. Um
kind of same as always. Right now, just
continuing doing research. Um I think I
mentioned last month
that um found some really great articles
about some um African-American social
groups here in town. And so, I've been
following a lot of those leads.
Um I've also been in contact with Aubrey
Edwards in Laramie, and I'm sure some
folks know her. She's kind of a
powerhouse
in um
uh History Matters.
Um and so, she's also um willing to help
out with this project, too. And cuz
she's doing some um research that's kind
of
um
uh
similar to what uh we're kind of working
on here, too. So,
uh her and I are going to share some of
our research together. So, that's pretty
exciting.
Um and then, airport terminal. Yep,
still trying to reach out to the base um
and their archivist there to get some
more information about the missile
program itself and how the airport
terminal was a part of that,
too. So,
um still moving forward on that stuff.
Um but, my big question is if the checks
have been cut, if there's any update on
that.
>> Um Chair, for you. So, our office
manager and accounting are still working
together. That Every time they think
they're just about to cut the checks,
something else comes up and it gets
delayed. It Every
The processes are being learned um as we
go by staff.
Um so,
they are and we just got a check also
from
Cheyenne Arts, which had to be
given to us prior to paying you.
Um so,
they've sent me information today that
said that they should be cutting the
checks next week.
Unfortunately, I know we've heard this
before, but hopefully this time it
really is happening.
>> Yeah.
>> Um we're supposed to get um
Desiree at the Arts Council said she
sent the check last like Wednesday, and
so we should be getting it in the mail
any second.
>> So the you guys can't issue payment
until you receive payment from Art
Cheyenne.
>> That's what I've been told.
>> Um
>> All right.
For the airport terminal, but for the
other piece
Well, how many months old is
>> Half a year.
>> Yeah, it's been six since October
is when the contracts were originally
signed. Um I have to say I am
disappointed to say that I did bring two
letters with me tonight of notice of
default and intent to terminate for both
of these projects.
Um so obviously, or if people aren't
familiar with those, are based on the
contract. Um since I haven't both
contracts um since I haven't been paid,
um I am asking the city to pay me within
15 days. And if they do not, then I have
the right to um
terminate the contract um and no longer
fulfill that. So um I did bring those
for both contracts today. Um I plan on
emailing them to you guys and um
obviously our president and vice chair
um as well.
Uh so that way we have a paper trail of
those two. So
just wanted that to be known and put
into the minutes um for the board
tonight as well.
>> So is there anything that we can do as
far as like talking to Robin directly to
execute cuz this would be a
terrible loss. We put so many years and
time into getting this, and we I mean
and I
I'm assuming you've probably slowed down
some of your work as well because of
non-payment. And can we even meet our
deadline by the end of this year? And
so, I
>> Tara, I think the letter that she's
going to provide is probably going to be
very, very good.
>> Okay.
>> I've wanted to pay this out of our
different accounts since the first
invoice came in, but I've been stuck um
at a level through our finance
department where we've had to go through
these different hoops. So, it's
>> Well, hopefully by
>> move forward.
>> issuing these letters, it'll jump-kick
actual payment. Um cuz
I mean, I completely understand um
I cuz it gets to a point when if you're
not being paid and not knowing you're
going to get paid
and slowing down the work, if you can
even achieve the goal of completing. So,
um
Well,
yeah, I mean, obviously, if you can
email that to Charles and Aaron, and
then obviously to us and physical
copies, I mean,
yeah.
Yes, any other comments on the other
items that Elizabeth presented? Um
We'll go ahead and move forward. Um oral
histories projects.
>> Um I don't have a huge update on this. I
was hoping this month um I wanted to do
an oral history with uh Ben Trail Wine,
who Charles had given me contact
information that he was sort of like a
silent partner with the Green Door for
in the last few years of its existence.
Um unfortunately, he is not interested
in participating in in oral history. So,
um so, that's not going to um go
forward, but um
I think um
I don't know. I feel like
pretty
good about the the ones I have collected
and I think that's pretty much as far as
I'm going to go with collecting stories
from from the Green Door and might
um
this next month turn my attention to
maybe looking for some other folks in
the community with
>> I do have a contact for you. So, um I
was talking to a gentleman actually at
Chronicles and there's
two sisters that were involved with the
the Hoffman building and just um a
parent
I think it was I think they said Hoffman
and maybe now questioning whether that's
the correct information. But anyways, it
sounds like you know, they they lived
here all their lives and um
think they're in their 80s now, but they
would love to share the kind of history
around the building that they grew up in
and and owned and and
>> Cool.
>> So, I'll I'll email that information to
you.
>> That sounds great. Cuz I don't know
where the Hoffman building is.
So, yeah, cool.
>> [laughter]
>> It's probably like not even Hoffman.
It's probably somewhere else and I just
don't know I misheard it. But she did
write it on a piece of paper, so I I do
have it on a piece of paper.
>> [laughter]
>> And then I don't I ran into Patrick
Bustos and mentioned that he was maybe
meeting with you about oral histories. I
don't know if you have
anything you want to share, Chuck.
>> No, no, I'm good. Go on.
>> Uh historic preservation month
Um
I apologize. I don't have that in front
of me. Who's the chair? Who's heading
that one?
Is it David or you?
Doing historic preservation month?
>> Uh
I'm on the committee. I can't remember
if I'm the head thing on there. I don't
know about the mayor's proclamation or
something about that it was
It's Patrick. No.
>> It's Patrick. Oh man, I'm sorry. I
should have had that pulled up, but I I
did not. Well,
Yes.
Patrick Boosts Yes.
>> [laughter]
>> I guess the city needs to answer about
the mayor's proclamation. Is that on
track? I think last year last month you
mentioned.
>> Yep, it's set up for May 11th at 2:00.
So, if anyone wants to go to that,
they're welcome to come.
Well, I do
I do have a look for Jones application.
I apologize. I I only have a paper copy
here. Um
but and I know you wanted to kind of
discuss
um
the Albany as well. Um but I do have it
for the Asher building. Think everyone's
pretty familiar with the Asher. It is on
the national register. Built 1905. It
was owned by the Asher family um who had
a wholesale grocer. Um you know,
currently occupied by Chronicles
Distillery, Art Cheyenne, and Cashwa
Grocers, which is I think pretty fitting
considering that used to be a a grocer's
before. Um but I I did go in and I um
I wanted to bring a lot of light to
Chronicles Distillery just because I
think that they kind of took that
warehouse space and kind of captured a
lot of the um elements that are um in
there and just you know, it's a really
big community hub and now Art Cheyenne
has moved in. Um so, I had talked to
Aaron at Chronicles um and he introduced
me to the owner of the building and was
able to go through and and take photos
and what you'll see in here is um some
of the historic photos and documentation
of the building. Um and just kind of
what the condition of the building is in
now and I just think as far as, you
know, adaptive reuse and keeping the
building active and and they're very um
appreciative and understanding of of
their historic structure um and continue
to just kind of
keep it alive. So, I don't I guess I
pass that way and you pass Yeah.
Um so, that's one consideration for the
Lur Jones um that I'm hoping we can look
at. And then David, I don't know if you
wanted to talk about the Albany.
>> Yeah, talked to the present owner and
the previous uh Callus family and uh
there's
the the second and third floor are
probably still historic, but the lower
level has had some uh uh enough
modification that it's probably not at
least for another 10 years
eligible uh and uh they also suffered a
lot of hail damage that they had to
replace a bunch of windows, which were
not was replaced with historic
members and the uh
the neon sign was totaled also. They're
going to try to get that repaired, but
uh basically that's going to be not be
brought forward for the award at this
time. So,
>> So, I I guess at this time we just have
this one application for the Lur Third
Jones. Um we can move it forward, but I
we obviously
can continue looking for other
applicants. We just won't hit that May
May time frame of giving an award. Um
so, we can kind of talk about that. I
don't Has anyone submitted anything for
the DuBois?
No.
>> Um the deadline was Friday and nothing
was submitted.
>> Yeah, we were going to give the DuBois
later, you know,
usually in the fall since it's a
you know, a lot of people are travel or
you know, vacationing during the or the
starting in May. And so the businesses
will be there but uh
usually uh we do the uh
Dubois like in the fall before the
weather gets bad. But uh
yeah, I don't I thought there was two
other buildings that were mentioned for
the uh
uh
>> It was the Alexis Drake building. I was
unable to contact her, so that's why I
reached out to the Yeah, no. Went and
talked to Asher.
Um
I can't remember the What was there?
>> Patrick Bustos has that uh
place he likes the uh audio hearing
center.
Um but he's not here tonight.
>> Okay.
>> Yep.
>> Um so I I guess
So basically we didn't get anything for
Dubois award even though we opened it
for um submissions and everything. Um so
maybe just setting that aside for the
minute and just talking about the
Leclerc Jones. Um
I mean basically it it sounds like you
Ambersary feel like it's uh would be a
worthy recipient of the award for their
sort of ongoing work preserving the
building.
>> Yep.
>> What have have they done recent
projects or updates or is it sort of
just like the ongoing
>> Just the ongoing and then you know, Art
Cheyenne obviously just moved in and
again they've you know, just done their
best to um you know, leave the existing
exposed structure uh the wood beams and
um columns and um leave as much as that
uh of the existing wood floors they can.
Um you know, leaving the exposed brick
where they can. Um you know, it being a
warehouse, there's not like a whole lot
of details internally. Um but they do
try to do their best to you know,
maintain the historic window frames um
and just yeah, ongoing maintenance on it
really. Um, it is on the the national
register, um,
which I I think is a plus.
Um, and I when I talked to the building
owner, I mean, again, she was just super
excited, um,
and she would if selected, they would
love to make it a celebration, um,
and just bring more light. They do have
they
did have a little plug in there that
they do have some tenant space. So, if
anyone needs
>> [laughter]
>> But, it it is a pretty cool building and
I I know a lot of us have probably all
been there with, you know, various
entities,
um, upstairs and events and
um, I know they were doing concerts for
a long time. They're not really doing
that anymore on that second floor, but
yeah.
And I do think it's kind of
interesting that they they they have a
grocer in there. I mean, that's what the
purpose of the building was and
>> Well, I think it I mean, I think it
seems like a good, um,
a good option for us to consider, um, if
we want to, you know, maybe take a vote
on it. Um, I know we we missed doing the
little Clark Jones last year. So, we
already skipped a year. So, I don't
think we want to skip another year, um,
to keep the award active,
um,
and I mean, we only have really received
information about, uh, two two different
buildings and sort of the guidance from
David was that the,
um, the other one isn't, um,
not a good moment for for the other
building,
um,
and I mean, I think this the
the process has been similar to years in
the past where we've we've really only
had a couple options previously, also.
So, I don't think that this is super out
of
um
line for for things in the past, so um
depending on what the rest of the board
thinks, I think it's
could be a good option.
>> Yeah, yeah, I'm not sure it's before my
time, but it there
it's my understanding that there was a
railroad line that went right along
these buildings there, and that's why
the
the they could run this this merchandise
or the grocery, you know, the
the I I think somebody told me that they
used to bring bananas and stuff in by
uh some sort of refrigerated or
semi-refrigerated thing, and they they
uh
he was putting it on his shoulder, and
every once in a while a tarantula would
crawl out
>> [laughter]
>> and stuff, but that's kind of why that
the level of the buildings the way they
are is cuz uh the the uh boxcars they're
sit up high enough, so
>> That makes sense.
>> And I guess I would also
go up ahead with approving that uh
or at least voting on it. I would vote
yes, so
>> Yeah, I apologize. I just had one
printed copy.
>> [laughter]
>> And the de Boys I'm kind of
if we didn't get any applicants, we
don't really have any recommendations,
so I don't know if we should just open
it back out for people to potentially
apply, and maybe we'll just need to do
some work at
trying to find
a house ourselves.
So
>> Yeah, I think I think we've got several
more months, and I think we could just
keep hopefully advertising. I'm
surprised we didn't get any
>> Yeah.
>> nominations this time, so
>> Well, we had all we had talked about um
doing like a paid Facebook
advertisement for that that I don't
think
we ever got around to it. Elizabeth, did
you see that I did add you to the
Facebook?
>> Yes, and of course I got on there too
late in order to promote it before the
deadline. So, I was going to say thank
you and apologize for dropping the ball
on
Oh, I forgot one more thing on in the
Chronicles Distillery area is is the old
safe. And so, they had that door open.
Um but you can still kind of see all the
components and then the area where, you
know, the employees had their little
cubbies for mail and so, that's still
kind of all intact.
Which is fun.
I didn't get to go to the basement. I
was a little disappointed in that cuz
basement's always the coolest part of
the building, but
>> I wonder what's down there.
>> Yeah.
Well, I know that that that their
distillery is down there cuz that's
where they make all the
alcohol, but I didn't get to see that.
May maybe if if they get this little
they'll let us see it.
>> [laughter]
>> Like I want to see the old boiler.
>> Simply one.
>> Yeah. Well, yes.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, I know I think people are still
looking at the pictures, but um in the
meantime, I guess I I would make a
motion that we um
nominate the Asher building for
the 2026 LeClerc Jones award.
>> I'll second.
>> I guess all all in favor say I.
I.
>> I.
>> Opposed?
>> We need to have a discussion.
>> Oh, yes, discussion. I apologize. We
were discussing for so long. I just
Was there any discussion?
No, okay.
Any discussion? No.
All right, all in favor?
>> I.
>> Any opposed?
Motion passes.
Um and I will contact Erin and just
figure out what
weekend um
works for them in in May so we can
schedule an open house and um
get that information to you guys so we
can create a plaque and
>> Like did you say it's like 4 to 6 weeks
to get that or
>> It's usually about that.
>> Okay, so maybe [clears throat] aim for
the end of May.
>> [laughter]
>> Erin, what do you what do you need from
us to
get that forward? Just whatever
information she Amber's already thinking
about. Is there other specific things
you need from us to like move forward
with purchasing the plaque?
>> Um I think just the plaque we can we can
go ahead and purchase it now cuz we
don't put
the date of the um event on. We just put
I think we just put this year
>> Okay.
>> on it so we can go ahead and start that
process.
>> Do we need to uh
vote on how much money or to approve the
the spending or is that through the does
the city uh take care of that plaque?
>> Um I think last year we just we didn't
vote on it. We just ordered it and paid
it through historic preservation funds.
>> Okay.
Okay, great. Yeah, I'll probably give
this copy um
to Erin so you guys have the
um
property owner's information.
Um and I'll contact them. Oh, go ahead.
>> I just wanted to note that the funding
for those awards remained in the budget
for a fiscal year 2027. No questions
asked.
>> [laughter]
>> Great.
>> And then once you have the dates for
um the event, just let us know so we can
post it or we can do a um
a social media post. Okay, perfect.
Great.
Well, that'll be exciting. I just I mean
a great group of people and obviously
they were just very excited um to talk
about their building and the history of
it and
so I think this will be a good one.
Um and then Dubois, if So, when you say
that it uh closed to
do the applications like so no one can
enter after today like so you have to
reopen it.
Okay. We would have to um let Matt
Murphy know. Okay. We need to reopen it
and pick another date. Okay. Um if we're
not going to
do this until the fall, I mean do we
want to give ourselves till like July to
receive applications?
So.
>> I would think maybe uh
like you get through the Leclerc Jones
um and make sure we get that
accomplished and then think about
reopening for Dubois, but in the
meantime I think we could make a plan
for
all the board members to be thinking
about
residences um that should be considered
for it as well.
>> Okay.
Um
So maybe we we reopen it and just like
is it like do does he have to have a
date or can we just have it open
until
we have an end date? I mean I think we
can just open it till
till whenever. It's just when usually
when we open it, we do um
um a social media blast and so we put
all the information in there when they
can
um when they can nominate till.
Got you.
Okay.
Um well, I think we should at least
reopen it and have it open until July
and that way we have time to receive and
then also if we come up with any, then
hopefully by August we can look at cuz I
mean we don't want to get too far into
the fall before we do it just cuz
I mean this winter wasn't good but
you never know what this upcoming year
is going to bring so.
So yeah, could we just
have it open till like the end of July?
Yeah, we can do that.
I guess anything else on historic
preservation month?
Um
Oh, uh
the pump well, I guess that's coming up
in the pump house. Um I don't have all
the information yet. I know that
Alliance was looking at doing another
tour of the pump house on the 17th of
May but there hasn't been any
I don't think there's been any official
um
times or
communication set
for that.
Have Charles have you heard anything?
>> I've not heard anything but if um Megan
Stampfer with the Alliance is going to
do that, she'll need to reach out to our
compliance department to get that um
ball rolling.
It is a much easier process now that
there's a door that opens and closes
that doesn't require a screwdriver and
all sorts of other stuff so um it's it's
easier so we'll
we'll check with compliance to make sure
that's moving forward.
>> And people need to sign that permission
slip or whatever you call it to to do
the tour again.
>> And Chair three, that is correct. And
Chair, also I don't know if we've
updated you all on this or not um but
you may have I don't recall the exact
time frame but you all may have noticed
that the fencing has been removed. Have
we talked about this yet? Okay. So the
fencing's removed to give it more
visibility and more awareness and to
prevent um illicit activity from
occurring where people think they're
safe and they can pick and pry and break
into the building, so there's more eyes
on it.
>> Great.
Anything else on historic preservation
month
before we move on? Okay.
Uh education of the public in historic
preservation  marketing.
>> Uh I found another copy of that historic
homes that I
gave to you or that I'm going to donate
to the St. Mary's to the teacher that
does the the
class over there. And I'm still trying
to track down to see uh that there was a
video that was created of about eight 18
or 20
houses here in Cheyenne back in the
1990s, and for a while it was on the
internet, but that
um hoping it's still out there in the
cloud somewhere, and it's just the link
has been expired, so.
>> Uh yeah, I also have some social media
updates. Again, thank you, Josh, for
your for doing that. Um but some two
posts that we um talked about as a
committee, uh tomorrow, the 15th, um
Shippo has sent out their statewide
plan. Um they're looking for feedback on
that.
It's their 10-year plan, so they're just
asking
anybody and everybody
to supply comments on that. Um so I
thought that would be a good partnership
of us to um share that on our socials.
So, that's uh the plan for tomorrow. The
other one is the week of the 27th is
preservation week.
Um so I was hoping we could share
something, obviously, about doing
[clears throat] that as well. Um
the day I'm kind of like going back and
forth, and I was curious about folks'
opinions um of taking a positive or
negative spin. I would prefer a positive
one. Um but the 26th is the date that
the Carnegie Library in town was
demolished in '71. Um, so that could be
an easy tie-in of why preservation is
important, but also I didn't know if
maybe we'd rather take a different spin
on that week and do um
a success story here in town instead.
So.
>> That's this April or this month.
>> Yeah, April 27th. So, I'm trying to look
at, you know, from our meeting through
to the next meeting. So, that's also
looking at the beginning of May as well.
So, that way things don't fall off my
my plate.
>> Yeah, Josh.
>> I feel like you could do both maybe. A
success and I mean people have very
strong opinions about the Carnegie
Library in particular for whatever
reason. That building in particular like
draws out lots and lots of negative
comments about the city letting it get
torn down and everything.
>> Well, we get lots of comments.
>> Yeah, that's yeah. But we could do both
like a success and a yeah.
>> Yeah, I looked up there's some articles
in in the library over here and
apparently
it was it was actually a county library,
so it was a county that demolished it,
but uh it was cheaper to tear it down
and sell the land than it was to fix the
leaky roof.
>> Hm.
Well.
>> I mean that's the that's the reason
people give for tearing down every
historic building.
>> I mean yeah, we could we could say that
about the airport terminal right now,
too, but
we won't get into that.
No, I I agree with Josh. I think if we
do like a positive and a negative, I
think the Carnegie Library it will bring
a lot of traction and and that's
probably a good thing cuz I mean when
we're looking at the pump house luckily
we there's a use for that now, but other
historic structures that are
potentially, you know, fading away.
Like, oh, we don't want to lose another
one. So, yeah.
But then we can maybe pick a I don't
know which one would be a good success
story right now, but
I I think we could do both.
>> Okay, great. I will um take that moving
forward. And yeah, I was kind of looking
at the frequency which um Don was trying
to post and I think other folks too um
and looking at just real briefly
scrolling
of our the most successful posts were
obviously historic posts.
Um so, including images and, you know,
some historic context and things like
that. So, um trying to look at that and
keep us um moving that [clears throat]
way forward. I think will help us be
pretty successful.
>> I think another thing that we could
share on our uh page is you know, the
DDA um is looking at doing the banners
and um
I think that would be a good one for us
to share.
>> What's that?
>> The the replacing the the banners that
we have around downtown and, you know,
bringing actually some historic, you
know, graphic representation, but it
right now there's a
RFP or RFQ or something. Oh, do you want
to come and you you
you come and talk about that.
>> I am Cass Rafa, the programs coordinator
for the DDA, and I um have kind of
revamped the banner program. Those
banners have been up since 2022 that are
downtown right now, so they're um
definitely at the end of their life. So,
I've um we put out an artist open call
um
for artists to submit artwork for the
banners.
Um and one of the [clears throat]
requirements is to
include at least one or more historical
photos of downtown Cheyenne or Rodeo CFD
type. Um so that call ends May 18th and
then we'll
see what all we get and
make it as cohesive as possible.
>> [laughter]
>> So
just trying to build that place making
and in the greater story of Cheyenne as
a whole and I've had a lot of fun
looking at historic pictures cuz I put
together like a Google Drive
for approved pictures for them to use.
Um and I
looked at um Old West Museum, uh
American Heritage Center, the Clark
Jones um at the library and all of these
and
I hope we get some good things. So
any questions on that?
>> Yeah, is there anything we can do to
support you? Like do you think sharing a
social media post or doing Absolutely.
support you for a call for art? Like
what can we do?
>> Yeah. Um Madam Chair, through you. Um
yeah. Sharing on social media would be
great. We do have a post up on our
Instagram and Facebook right now about
it. If you'd like to share it, it has
the link. Um
I have some flyers printed out I could
send to you even and then you could send
to the board. Um
>> Yeah, if you can send me the
>> the flyers.
So yeah, if that I don't know if you
would want the flyer to hand out or give
to people, but I can absolutely do that
too.
Yeah.
>> Thank you.
Guess anything else on marketing? Any
comments, questions?
Uh ornaments? Like Gary's not here, so I
unless
someone has spoken to him and he's given
you an update, then
Okay.
Um, Airport Fountain Planning, Kelly.
>> Yes. So, um, since our last meeting, we
did have a follow-up call with Pacific
Coast Conservation that had given us
the, um, quotes to come do some repairs
and testing, um, basically on
preserving the fountain, um, and trying
to reverse some of the damage that we've
seen from the spalling, um,
So, we got a little bit of clarification
from them on what they proposed and, um,
I know last meeting we had talked about
their
option two, which was like a full
removal of the epoxy fill and coating
that was previously applied, um, that
they didn't actually price, but we were
curious like if you do this testing, can
you then give us a price for that? And
they still kind of reiterated they don't
necessarily recommend that and it's more
because that ri- there's a risk of
removing a lot of the original material
from the terracotta.
So, it sounds like their their
recommendation still is to come up with
some sort of ongoing spot treatment
plan.
Um, but we did get an updated proposal
from them based on the discussion and
the board approval last meeting to move
forward with this initial testing and,
um,
let them do some fills and coatings and
add some weep holes to the bottom of the
fountain, which we're hoping will help
with the drainage so there's not as much
moisture infiltration into the
terracotta itself. So, um,
we got them a
a signed proposal. It was around It was
right around $9,100
The approval was to spend up to 10,000
for this initial testing phase.
And I just got from Giselle today um a
purchase order from the city since that
is going to be contracted directly from
the city to Pacific Coast Conservation
for what we had agreed to move forward
with.
And um have not had a chance to review
that, but I'll send that out unless
there's anything else you need me to do
with that, Aaron. I'll just pass that on
to Pacific Coast if it
matches the proposal that we had.
Okay.
Um so they do have us um
scheduled for the week of, I believe it
was May 15th.
I can't remember the exact date, but
they're planning to be here.
Maybe the 11th. Maybe I'm confusing that
with the mayor's
proclamation.
Uh
let's see. I think I know.
May May 11th. You're You're right.
Yep. So they are planning to be up here
um Lucinda, who's their main
uh
conservationist, I think was her title.
She'll be here that whole week to do
some um
testing and spot treatment. And then the
plan is to probably wait a full year.
And the reason being we want to let the
fountain run during the summer months
and then let it go through a freeze-thaw
cycle in the winter and see how that um
holds up.
And then probably have them I mean
they'll give us recommendations for
ongoing maintenance and and treatment. I
also did reach out to Jason Sanchez at
the city just to make sure he was in the
loop on what we're planning and got an
email back from him. Um
and he said they're good with that. They
won't plan to start up fill and start
the fountain until after that's all
complete. We'll just keep them in the
loop. Um but he also recommended
for our consideration, he said we should
replace the plumbing and nozzles in the
fountain.
Um he said
and this is good information to have
the that their team had worked to repair
and keep the fountain running through
the summer months, but the met some of
the metal plumbing is corroded, which
has caused a metal flake to come off and
clog the filter and the nozzles. So he
said last year the city spent about
$2,000 of their funds on plumbing
repairs.
And he listed what some of those were.
And then they've spent a lot of their
staff hours as well to try and keep the
fountain operational. So I haven't done
anything with that yet. I probably need
to reach out to Millward maybe. And
Patrick, I don't know if you had any
information. Welcome back. Um good to
see you. But um I think we were going to
look into who did some plumbing updates
previously. I don't know if that was the
>> Yeah, I don't really have any
information on the plumbing.
I know [clears throat] the gentleman
from the city that met me out there
told me that they'd had a plumber come
in and uh
He had indicated to me that all the
plumbing had been redone.
>> Right.
>> But I you know, I still have pictures of
down there and I'll I'll go back and
look and see what they're talking about
this metal
plumbing that's
um
having issues. See if I can I if I've
got that photo of that or something
because I I took extensive photos when I
was down there in the pit.
>> I don't recall there being any um
updating to any of the piping plumbing
portion. I think the only thing we did
was replace the pump itself. So that
could it could very well be old piping
corroded. Yeah. Um and I I think when So
Kelly and I do anticipate meeting with
uh Pacific Coast when they come and um
coordinating. So we you know, we'll take
a deeper dive into evaluating that um
because obviously we'll need
Jason to let us in to that bottom
portion, but we can investigate that
further that week.
>> Okay. And if you'd like to let me know,
I can be back involved if
>> Okay.
>> my health stays okay.
>> Yeah, no, we can absolutely let you
know.
>> Thank you. And I'm glad to see that that
company is
coming about and
having some active stuff going on here.
>> Yes, thank you for initiating that. It
took us a while to gather all the
information and get to a plan, but I
think it's a step in the right
direction.
>> Yeah, you bet.
Good.
>> Josh.
>> Um yeah, I'm I'm not surprised about the
nozzles. I feel like just even driving
past, um you could when the fountain was
running, you could see like some, you
know, cuz there's probably what, like 80
nozzles all the way around or something,
and you could see that some of them were
like not spraying correctly or like
yeah, or doing a very like yeah, yeah,
yeah.
Um
so I'm not I'm not surprised by that,
but yeah, thanks to everybody on that
committee for getting all of that moving
forward.
>> Just just a note, when I met again with
the city of uh maintenance guy there,
he said it he indicated it wasn't the
nozzles so much as there is a strainer
down there, and it gets clogged with
everything, you know, leaves, uh bird
feathers that go into the strainer, and
then clog the pump. And that's why
I mentioned him one day I would go by
there, and it's shooting like Old
Faithful, and the next day I go by, and
it's like 2 in high. And he said, "Well,
that's because the pump strainer
constantly needs to be cleaned."
>> Hm.
>> So, um
I I don't know if that has an impact on
the nozzles or not. I imagine it does.
So, and it could be clogging from all
that that gets through the strainer. So,
it's it's it's something to try and keep
that thing going.
So, they indicated that to me and I
could see going down in the pit. If you
go down there, make sure you take an
umbrella because I don't know the water
is penetrating the ceiling and it's
leaking all over the place down there.
Um
from the fountain up above. That's I
don't know Pacific Coast is going to
address that.
Uh if you look in there, you can see
it's been
um patched together
Mhm.
where the water hits and then somehow
it's soaking all the way down into the
the lower level. I
>> Got you.
>> So,
>> Yeah, I think there'll be a lot of
investigating that week and um
you know, between
the three of us and and with Pacific
Coast, hopefully we can really get to
the bottom of it and I it's really
unfortunate. I think we were all hoping
for, you know, another really great
completion of the fountain and you know,
that we're going to have to wait another
year, but you know, when we were talking
with Pacific Coast, if we try and rush
it and rush that timeline, we might be
back in the same position we're in now
and that would also be unfortunate. So,
um
I
I do think we need to do it right. So.
>> Most definitely.
>> So, I'll follow up um I'll reach back
out to Jason and then Milward as well
and just see if they have any
information on, you know, plumbers that
have worked on it in the past and then I
can do a little additional investigation
to see if there's other like fountain
specialty contractors or something like
if we're going to be out there that week
investigating, maybe we bring somebody
else in that might have more expertise
on those components.
>> Yeah, I think that would be
a really good idea.
Um
I would think they could at least at it.
I don't know
I don't know if
Are you thinking that we would
contract someone else to or hopefully
they'll just kind of take a look at it.
>> Right.
>> Just get them out there.
>> Okay. Like get eyes on it initially and
see what their thoughts are. I don't
think we'd
be offering to spend any money for them
to come do that. Right. Just see if
somebody's willing to come
>> look at it.
>> Look at it.
>> It Anything else
>> on airport
>> Fountain planning? Any questions,
comments? Okay. Uh
Pump house. I mean, I I think we've
pretty much covered that. I guess
Charles, is there any update on just
kind of the progress of construction?
>> Madam Chair, members of the board, I
haven't heard any updates on that. I
believe it's still ongoing. I think they
just awarded the contract recently.
>> I think that's right. Yeah.
Uh will they I mean, I know we've talked
about this before, but at at some point
in the planning, will they come and
present to us what the plan is for the
pump house just so
we know.
>> Madam Chair, to the members of the
board,
we are aware of that and will be making
the request for them to do that. I would
hope that they would do that. I'd be
surprised if they didn't.
>> Design guidelines, um we met uh I I
actually can't remember if it was a
couple weeks ago.
And kind of just started the process of
gathering information. Um I did actually
find out recently that there was another
version of design guidelines that were
put together in 2017-ish. Um and I was
going to ask if if the that was
in the city files anywhere or if it's
just kind of
gone with the wind.
Um
Yeah, so
Desiree with Art Shrian
when she was
with the DDA DDO now.
Oh, okay.
Oh, yeah.
Anyways, we were we were just kind of
trying to gather all the the variations
that have been done and looking at a lot
of examples. Thank you for sending those
were phenomenal and I think really gives
us a good head start and so we we
determine how we're going to approach it
and I think the way that we've decided
to move forward is we're going to kind
of
review each district individually and to
starting with the downtown district so
we can get that moving forward so that
the DDA has guidelines to work with as
far as like the facade improvement
grants and and so forth. Um and we were
planning to meet this week but I think
might be maybe next week. We're trying
to determine that day.
Do you want to
>> Just really fast. Um I will kind of be
your DDA liaison for this because it is
in a the plan of development
implementation matrix as you know. So um
and we did send I believe we sent any
past ones to planning staff to start
reviewing what we have in our files. Um
but if there is anything else you need
from the DDA
have your staff reach out to me. I'll be
your person for that.
>> Awesome. Thank you so much.
>> Yeah. And I'll be at these meetings too.
So.
>> Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> And I'll see you on Thursday at yours.
>> [laughter]
>> Um
Well, and I think you got you sent us
the 1990s version or we we got it from
somewhere.
Charles, do do cuz there was like a
1990s version.
And
>> Hi Amber. Um sorry if I'm talking out of
turn. This is Sophia Maze. Uh I sent it
to you all.
I sent you like the 1990s version and
then I think one from 2007. Um Cass will
look through our
our physical records as well to see if
we can find any more, but that's what I
had digitally.
>> Okay.
>> And sure, yes, I was having to jog my
memory to remember the design
guidelines, but yes, I do remember that
those were dug up during the DDA plan of
development.
>> So.
>> Yeah, and
I think we have those. I just I
Desiree said that there was an even
current one, but I I sounds like no one
has that copy, so.
Like I've like 2017-ish.
Sophia, do you know?
>> Oh, um I don't know. I don't see it in
my digital records. So, I when I combed
through when you guys were doing your
strategic planning, um what I sent you
was what I had, but I have not looked
through our vault files yet. So, there
might be something there, for sure.
>> Okay.
Um so, yeah, we're
moving that forward, I guess. Josh, do
you
have any additional comments to
>> No, just that yeah, we're
starting to look at it, so.
>> Yeah.
Um watch list items.
I guess does anyone have any
updates on on any of these? I I don't
really
have anything on the governor's mansion
or towards the schools clo- the
closing of the schools, the Van Tassel
carriage,
and the demolition by neglect ordinance.
I I don't think we're trying to pick up
right now, so.
>> [laughter]
>> Um do you guys have any information of
uh of the school closings and what's
happening with
>> Um chair, through you. I mean, the
Deming is on
um slated for closing this year, and
they do have a
end of period or end of year party
scheduled. I think it's
in May sometime.
Is that something anyone's interested in
attending? Just
It's May 7th.
Is that open to the public or I believe
so. I just saw it on Facebook.
Okay.
Okay. Um any
new business anyone like to bring forth?
Yes, Patrick.
>> Madam Chairman, I'd like to mention that
the
Atlas open house is this weekend,
Saturday 18th at 6:00 after extensive uh
refurbishing. Um the Atlas
uh theater's going to be back open.
They'll give tours and things like that
and have all ders and stuff. So,
um appreciate it if everybody could come
down and take a look what we did.
Um
it was fun for me to be involved in all
that. Unfortunately, my health took a
turn and I couldn't finish it out, but
um it's all done and they got a
certificate of occupancy and ready to
go. So,
uh again, that's Saturday the 18th at
6:00. Doors open.
>> Awesome.
Is that something we can Did you guys
like have a a Facebook post or anything
about it that we could share on
>> It is. Yeah, there is one on Facebook
post on it.
I'm not sure.
Um they're going to have all ders.
They're going to have some uh
play presentations and they're going to
open open up and uh let everybody know
the schedule coming up for the plays and
things like that. So, it'll be fun. I've
seen some of what they've done and it
was a huge process.
It was amazing what they had to do to
that thing to to jack everything up and
um yeah, they would they would jack it
up a half inch a night and hope they
came back and it didn't crumble. So, it
was quite a process for them to go
through that and stuff and
so, um and then of course uh they had to
do a whole lot of different things that
weren't part of the schedule like
putting a brand new fire system, alarm
system, things like that. So, um
it was something else. So, but it's
it'll hold up for another 100 years, I'm
sure.
>> Awesome.
Exciting.
Does anyone else have any new business
you want to bring forth?
Uh old business. Sounds
put chair through. Um
our office manager has indicated that
there are a couple people who still need
to provide receipts for anything that um
you guys paid for at the conference for
Saving Places.
Um and then also
um if anyone has their parking receipt
as well.
But, I think she needed receipts from um
Chuck
Patrick Bustos and the new member.
And I did have a question because
so, I ended up having to pay for my
hotel room because
of the mix-up.
And but I was kind of told that I wasn't
going to get reimbursed for that. Should
I try and submit the receipt and hope
that I get reimbursed?
>> submit it. I've I've
vaguely heard that you can't be
reimbursed for it because we had already
paid for it through the credit card.
Um but
you could we could try.
Yeah.
Well, you guys should get a refund
because
well, you paid for a room that no one
slept in.
So, um okay.
Well, we'll all get on our reimbursement
receipts.
Uh
so, other business I guess we talked
about Are you going to go into this a
little bit further, Charles, with the
uh 418
West First Avenue?
>> Sorry, I have one more thing of other
business.
>> Yeah, I can't
>> For other business.
>> Uh okay.
Um
Well, I yeah, I mean, we did and talk
about that property, and it sounds like
you more information's going to come so
you don't we don't want to
you don't have anything else to discuss
on that.
>> Nope. We should be mailing that
information out on April 27th to you.
>> So, I guess other business?
>> Chair members of the board, I totally
forgot about this until
I just remembered it. So,
this is not a historic structure, but
this is not recognized as one, but this
is an old house right here. This is on
Bradley and 15th.
This is Holiday Park. This is the big
curve. Advance Auto Parts is right over
here. Supposedly, this is the original
We've heard the original signalman's
house for the railroad. Does anyone know
anything about the history of this
structure?
>> Um Gary Sims knows about it, but he's
not here tonight. I remember several
years ago Gary brought a picture and a
bunch of information about this
building.
That Yeah, that it's connected to
one of the railroads, not
the uh
UP. It was like a different rail line or
something.
>> There's the um
the CB&Q rail line which ran through
this area as well. This could have been
actually where the CB&Q joined the Union
Pacific main line. That would make
sense. Being in a signalman's house
right there at the merger of the two
items. Well, anyway, we have a
development proposal for this lot.
It's not a data center.
>> Oh, that's a relief.
>> No, it is What it actually is is
a person has indicated they wish to
restore this home. Um there is
not as a home, but they want to restore
the structure I should say, but there's
nothing really
mandating that it
be preserved in any way, but we can
always talk to them about it. Um they
would like to do essentially an auto
sales type of facility here where this
would be their office and then they
would do improvements on the site
including some sidewalk on the 15th
Street side and then some landscaping
and some display area out here while
this would be here. This would all go
through our board of adjustment through
the conditional use process. So, in the
event that they um are doing any
modifications building, we could put
some type of
a condition on there that it would
retain some historical elements. So,
anyway, just want to give you a heads-up
there's some stuff going on out there.
We don't know if it'll
move forward as
as is or in the early conversations with
this
this group just thought we'd
um pick your brains
to see if there were any
Is there anything we all needed to know
about that?
>> But yeah, I
>> Gary
>> talk to Gary because he he had done some
gathering of information about it. But
yeah, in general though, I think it
would be great if we could
find some way to
encourage or require some amount of
preservation of of what's there.
So, I don't know what you what you would
need from us
Charles as that moves forward like
what would be useful?
Like a letter from the board or
something or
>> No, nothing at this time. I was just
really just trying to take your your
all's temperature and knowledge level on
this. I'll be in touch with Gary.
>> I mean, obviously they're welcome to
come and talk to us if they
would like our opinion.
Oh, cool.
Um
nice to know that it might actually get
some use instead of
sitting boarded up.
Yeah, looks like there's some decorative
elements though.
>> There's
>> window and
>> two chimneys, which that's toasty.
>> Oh, cool.
Are there any other business?
Nope.
Okay, well, if there's nothing else, um
I move to adjourn.
Thanks. Thanks.
Yes, I I I don't know.